Rush family papers LCP.Rush
Library Company of Philadelphia
- Series I. Benjamin Rush papers
  - Subseries I: Correspondence
    - A. Bound volumes
      - Bellinger, R., 1797-1798 (Volume 2, Page 104-105)
      - Bend, Joseph, 1800 December 20 (Volume 2, Page 109)
      - Benon, J.A., 1797 April 1 (Volume 2, Page 115)
      - Bensell, George, 1801-1802, 1813 (Volume 2, Page 112-114)
      - Bentinck, J., undated (Volume 2, Page 110)
      - Beresford, Richard, 1800 May 12 (Volume 2, Page 116)
      - Bergsten, Nichol, 1801 January 26 (Volume 2, Page 111a-111b)
      - Betton, Samuel, 1790 June 23 (Volume 2, Page 117)
      - Betts, Thaddeus, 1795-1799 (Volume 2, Page 118-123)
      - Bevan, Joseph Gurney, 1786-1787, 1793 (Volume 2, Page 124-127)
      - Bevan, Timothy, 1770-1772 (Volume 2, Page 128-132)
      - Bevan, Timothy, 1774 July 27, 1785 February 2 (Volume 2a, Page 1-3)
      - Biglow, J., 1798 September 11 (Volume 2a, Page 22a-22b)
      - Birckhead, Chris, 1781-1784 (Volume 2a, Page 11-14)
      - Birckhead, Solomon, 1783-1811 (Volume 2a, Page 15-21)
      - Bird, H.M., undated (Volume 2a, Page 7-9)
      - Bird, Mark, undated (Volume 2a, Page 10)
      - Bissett, John, 1785 July 15 (Volume 2a, Page 24)
      - Black, Robert, 1794 January 26, 1800 January 30 (Volume 2, Page 70-71)
      - Black, Thomas, 1796 August 10 (Volume 2, Page 69)
      - Blaine, Ephraim, 1787 September 17-October 15 (Volume 2, Page 72-73)
      - Blaine, Ephraim and George Meade, 1787 July 4 (Volume 2, Page 74)
      - Blair, Samuel, 1802 November 15 (Volume 2, Page 75)
      - Blake, James, 1800 April 25 (Volume 2, Page 76)
      - Blay, George, 1803 June 29 (Volume 2, Page 77)
      - Blayney, Arthur, 1796 July 25 (Volume 2, Page 78)
      - Bledsoe, Rob, 1810 October 1 (Volume 2a, Page 4)
      - Blount, T., 1807 November 1 (Volume 2a, Page 31)
      - Blythe, James, 1807 April 28 (Volume 2a, Page 119)
      - Blythe, Stephen, 1811 March 14 (Volume 2a, Page 121)
      - Bohannon, Richard L., 1811-1812 (Volume 2a, Page 32-33)
      - Boland, James, 1808 October 4 (Volume 2a, Page 34)
      - Bond, R., undated (Volume 2a, Page 39a-39c)
      - Bond, Thomas E., 1803-1810 (Volume 2a, Page 35-38)
      - [Bostock], J., 1805 September 30 (Volume 2a, Page 40)
      - Boswell, Joseph, 1801 May 26, 1811 May 19 (Volume 2a, Page 41-42)
      - Boteten, Henderson Jim, 1801 April 6-1801 July 20 (Volume 2a, Page 43-44)
      - Bouske, J., 1792 September 21 (Volume 2a, Page 45)
      - Bowen, Mary, 1810 June 9 (Volume 2a, Page 47)
      - Bowen, Pardon, 1806 March 24 (Volume 2a, Page 46)
      - Bowen, William, 1797 December 8 (Box 15)
      - Bowie, J., 1814 July 6 (Volume 2a, Page 75)
      - Bowie, John, 1804 January 3 (Volume 2a, Page 48)
      - Bowie, Richard, 1802 October 8 (Volume 2a, Page 49)
      - Bowman, J., circa 1786-1803 (Volume 2a, Page 50-52b)
      - Bowman, S., undated (Volume 2a, Page 53)
      - Boyce, M., 1784 November 4 (Volume 2a, Page 54)
      - Boyd, William, 1800 June 29 (Volume 2a, Page 56)
      - Boyse, William, 1794 December 20 (Volume 2a, Page 55)
      - Bradley, Stephen, 1803 February 12 (Volume 2, Page 79)
      - [Bradthom], John, undated (Volume 2, Page 80)
      - Brailsford, Edward, 1798 July 14 (Volume 2, Page 82)
      - Brailsford, Elizabeth, 1797 June 21 (Volume 2, Page 81)
      - Brailsford, Elizabeth, 1798 November 27, undated (Volume 2, Page 83-84)
      - Brailsford, Samuel, 1795 October 13 (Volume 2, Page 85)
      - Brailsford, W., undated (Volume 2, Page 86a-86b)
      - Brailsford, W., undated (Volume 2, Page 87a-87b)
      - Branham, Henry, 1811 April 14 (Volume 2, Page 88)
      - Bravo, S., 1812 November 9 (Volume 2, Page 89)
      - Brenson, J., 1783 July 12 (Volume 2a, Page 5)
      - Brent, Richard, 1813 February 18 (Volume 2a, Page 6)
      - Briggs, J., 1798 April 25 (Volume 2a, Page 23)
      - Bright, Maria, 1793 November 29 (Volume 2a, Page 25)
      - Bright, Maria, undated (Volume 2a, Page 27-28)
      - Brickel, John, 1795 January 23 (Box 15)
      - Briscoe, J., 1801 June 9, 1801 August 27 (Volume 2a, Page 29-30)
      - [Brockenburg], J., 1796 August 5 (Volume 2a, Page 58)
      - Brodbelt, Rigby, 1795 January 6 (Volume 2a, Page 57)
      - Brodie, John, 1787 January 12, undated (Volume 2a, Page 59-60)
      - Broom, Jacob, 1809 September 28 (Volume 2a, Page 61-64)
      - Broom, Jacob, 1809 November 20 (Volume 2a, Page 73)
      - Brown, D., 1805 May 25 (Volume 2a, Page 65)
      - Brown, G.B., 1773, 1787 (Volume 2a, Page 71-72)
      - Brown, George, 1792-1801 (Volume 2a, Page 66-70)
      - Brown, John, undated (Volume 2a, Page 74)
      - Brown, Richard, 1819 January 6 (Volume 2a, Page 76)
      - Brown, Richard, undated (Volume 2a, Page 78)
      - Brown, Thomas, 1812 May 3 (Volume 2a, Page 77)
      - Brown, Samuel, 1797 September 20 (Volume 2a, Page 79)
      - Brown, Samuel, 1808 August 2 (Volume 2a, Page 81)
      - Brown, Thomas, 1808 November 7 (Volume 2a, Page 82)
      - Brown, Thomas S.R., 1811 (Volume 2a, Page 80)
      - Browne, William, 1773-1774, 1781 (Volume 2a, Page 83-86)
      - Bruce, James, 1793 January 5 (Volume 2a, Page 114)
      - Brundige, Timothy, 1813 February 9 (Volume 2a, Page 118)
      - Brunsmitt, F.B.K., 1782 June 8 (Volume 2a, Page 116)
      - Brunsmitt, Francis, 1812 June 8 (Volume 2a, Page 117)
      - Buchanan, A., 1770 April 14 (Volume 2a, Page 89)
      - Buchanan, George, 1797 September 3 (Volume 2a, Page 90a-90b)
      - Buchanan, J.A., 1801-1802 (Volume 2a, Page 93-100)
      - Buchanan, James, 1812 November 14 (Volume 2a, Page 92)
      - Buck, Marcus, 1812 October 29 (Volume 2a, Page 88)
      - Buck, Marcus, 1812 April 28 (Volume 2a, Page 91)
      - Bull, Lorenzo, 1809 November 20 (Volume 2a, Page 106)
      - Bullus, J., 1797, undated (Volume 2a, Page 107-108b)
      - Burd, Edward, 1807-1808 (Volume 2a, Page 101-102)
      - Burke, A., 1800 May 10 (Volume 2a, Page 103)
      - Burke, Richard, 1799 January 19 (Volume 2a, Page 105, 109)
      - Burns, J., 1807 August 6 (Volume 2a, Page 104)
      - Burton, Robert, 1804-1808 (Volume 2a, Page 110-112)
      - Burwell, Edwin, 1797 November 1 (Volume 2a, Page 115)
      - Burwell, William, 1810 December 26 (Volume 2a, Page 113)
      - Byng, Moses, 1794 September 11 (Volume 2a, Page 120)
      - C, [Yi2 7219] (Volume 3)
      - D-E, [Yi2 7220] (Volume 4)
      - F, [Yi2 7221] (Volume 5)
      - G, [Yi2 7222] (Volume 6)
      - H, [Yi2 7223] (Volume 7)
      - I-J, [Yi2 7224] (Volume 8)
      - K-L, [Yi2 7225] (Volume 9)
      - M, [Yi2 7226] (Volume 10)
      - M, [Yi2 7227] (Volume 11)
      - N-O, [Yi2 7228] (Volume 12)
      - P, [Yi2 7229] (Volume 13)
      - R, [Yi2 7230] (Volume 14)
      - S, [Yi2 7231] (Volume 15)
      - S, [Yi2 7232] (Volume 16)
      - T, [Yi2 7233] (Volume 17)
      - U-V, [Yi2 7234] (Volume 18)
      - Wa-Wl, [Yi2 7235] (Volume 19)
      - Wl-Yo, [Yi2 7236] (Volume 20)
      - A-P, [Yi2 7237] (Volume 21)
      - R-W, [Yi2 7238] (Volume 22)
      - A-W, [Yi2 7239] (Volume 23)
      - A-P, [Yi2 7240] (Volume 24)
      - R-W, [Yi2 7241] (Volume 25)
      - A-Y, [Yi2 7242] (Volume 26)
      - Drs. Barton, Cox, Hosack, and Miller, [Yi2 7243] (Volume 27)
      - Lettsom, Percival, Sharp, etc., [Yi2 7244] (Volume 28)
      - Controversial, [Yi2 7245] (Volume 29)
      - Belknap, Jeremy, 1787-1794 (Volume 30, Page 1-23)
      - Brekenridge, William, 1783-1806 (Volume 30, Page 24-26)
      - Ellicott, Andrew, 1802-1804 (Volume 30, Page 27-34)
      - Kosciuszko, General, undated (Volume 30, Page 35-38)
      - Baker, Saunders, Baillee, etc. regarding General Koscuoski's health, 1797 June 3 (Volume 30, Page 39a-39b)
      - Beddaes, Thomas, undated (Volume 30, Page 40)
      - Henry, James W., 1797-1799 (Volume 30, Page 41-43)
      - Dearborn, Henry, 1801 (Volume 30, Page 44-45)
      - Eustis, William, 1809 November 3 (Volume 30, Page 46)
      - Rush, Benjamin to William Eustis (copy), 1809 November 14 (Volume 30, Page 47)
      - Eustis, William, 1809-1812 (Volume 30, Page 48-55)
      - Priestly, Joseph, 1794-1803 (Volume 30, Page 56-67)
      - Cooper, Thomas regarding death of Dr. Priestly, 1804 February 6 (Volume 30, Page 68)
      - Priestly, Joseph, 1805 April 5 (Volume 30, Page 69)
      - Rush, Benjamin to Dr. Wistar (copy) regarding Dr. Priestly, 1801 March 12 (Volume 30, Page 70)
      - Priestly, Joseph (financial document), undated (Volume 30, Page 71)
      - Senter, J., 1791-1799 (Volume 30, Page 72-80)
      - Stone, Colonel (treatment of), undated (Volume 30, Page 81a-81b)
      - List of clothing washed, undated (Volume 30, Page 82)
      - Shaaf, John Thomas, 1787 August 10 (Volume 30, Page 83a-83b)
      - Coningham, Corn., 1787 August 19 (Volume 30, Page 84-85)
      - Harwood, Rich, 1787 August 24 (Volume 30, Page 86)
      - Stockett, M., 1787 (Volume 30, Page 87-88)
      - Stone, John Hoskins regarding treatment by Rush after Battle of Germantown, 1791 (Volume 30, Page 89-90)
      - Strong, Joseph, 1792 October 24 (Volume 30, Page 91)
      - Author unknown regarding case of tetanus, undated (Volume 30, Page 92)
      - Bondinot, undated (Volume 30, Page 93)
      - Brodbelt, Rigby, 1792 July 8 (Volume 30, Page 94)
      - Campbell, George W., 1792 August 16 (Volume 30, Page 95a-95b)
      - Annan, William regarding case of tetanus, 1793 July 22 (Volume 30, Page 96)
      - Author unknown, regarding tetanus, 1815 January (Volume 30, Page 97)
      - Annan, William regarding case of tetanus, undated (Volume 30, Page 98)
      - Carter, M., undated (Volume 30, Page 99)
      - Hartz regarding tetanus, undated (Volume 30, Page 100-101)
      - Ford, John regarding tetanus, 1786 June 4 (Volume 30, Page 102)
      - Nutt, Rush, 1810 March 15 (Volume 30, Page 103)
      - Causin, Nath. D., 1804 March 25 (Volume 30, Page 104)
      - Waterhouse, Benjamin, 1793-1812 (Volume 30, Page 105-120)
      - Webster, Noah, 1780-1803 (Volume 30, Page 121-141)
      - Dilly, Edward, 1770-1774; [Yi2 7247] (Volume 31, Page 1-10)
      - Dilly, Charles, 1778-1795; [Yi2 7247] (Volume 31, Page 11-29)
      - Pennsylvania Hospital, 1784-1812; [Yi2 7247] (Volume 31, Page 30-59)
      - Medical Society of Philadelphia, 1796-1800; [Yi2 7247] (Volume 31, Page 60-67)
      - University of Pennsylvania, 1789-1812; [Yi2 7247] (Volume 31, Page 68-99)
      - Land correspondence and papers, 1784-1812; [Yi2 7248] (Volume 32, Page 62-115)
      - Rush family letters, [Yi2 7249] (Volume 33)
      - Rush family letters and land papers, 1762-1809; [Yi2 7250] (Volume 34, Page 1-107)
      - Yellow Fever, 1793; [Yi2 7251] (Volume 35, Page 1-136)
      - Yellow Fever, 1793; [Yi2 7252] (Volume 36, Page 1-123)
      - Yellow Fever, 1793-1809; [Yi2 7253] (Volume 37, Page 1-74)
      - Yellow Fever, 1793-1811; [Yi2 7254] (Volume 38, Page 1-81)
      - Letters from Benjamin Rush, 1762-1813; [Yi2 7255] (Volume 39, Page 1-149)
      - Elizabeth Graeme Fergusson's letters and poems, 1771-1800; [Yi2 7256] (Volume 40, Page 1-158)
      - Dickinson College, 1782-1786; [Yi2 7258] (Volume 41, Page 2-176)
      - Dickinson College, 1786-1813; [Yi2 7259] (Volume 42, Page 1-172)
      - Letters to Benjamin Rush possibly regarding politics/nation building, etc., 1753-1812; [Yi2 7260] (Volume 43)
      - David Ramsay letters, probably about politics, nation building, etc., 1776-1813; [Yi2 7257] (Volume 45, Page 1-73)
    - B. Letters Removed from Volumes
      - Williams, Robert (volume 20, page 18), 1801 October 18 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Muhlenberg, Henry (volume 23, page 66), 1787 June 25 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Author unknown regarding vermicelli (volume 24, pages 110-111), 1802 November 4 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Prisoners in Philadelphia Prison (volume 21, page 7), 1800 September 16 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Clettson, J., 1793 July 31 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Rush Benjamin to Julia and unknown recipients regarding the controversies surrounding the military hospitals during the Revolutionary War (volume 29, pages 120a-120c), 1778-1812 (Box 1, Folder 6-8)
      - List of maniacal patients in the Pennsylvania Hospital (volume 31, page 33), 1804, February 15 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Rush Benjamin to the Managers of the Pennsylvania Hospital regarding treatment of the mentally ill (volume 31, page 54), 1811 November 23 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Medical students requesting Rush to publish his lectures (volume 31, page 71), 1791 February 2 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Medical students requesting Rush to publish his lectures on Animal Life (volume 31, page 74), 1799 January 2 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Cochran, [Alex] to Dr. Fisher (volume 35, page 24), 1793 October 18 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - Coates, Josiah L. (volume 35, page 30), 1793 September 23 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - Author unknown regarding yellow fever (volume 35, page 34), 1793 September 11 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - Morris, M. (volume 35, page 77, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Meredith, M. (volume 35, page 82), undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - Hazard, Ebenezer from Benjamin Rush (volume 39, page 8), 1765-1768 (Box 1, Folder 18-21)
      - Bill for drugs imported from England (volume 39, page 32), 1783 October 16 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - Recipient unknown from Benjamin Rush regarding prisons (volume 39, page 40), 1789 October 14 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      - J.B. (a free Negro) with sonnet (volume 39, page 41), 1791 July 24 (Box 1, Folder 24)
      - Recipient unknown from Benjamin Rush regarding fees for postage (volume 39, page 54), 1798 December 29 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      - Recipient unknown from Benjamin Rush (volume 39, page 67), 1805 March 22 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      - Epitaph on John Barry by Benjamin Rush (volume 39, page 111), 1805 March 7 (Box 1, Folder 27)
      - Constitution of the Philadelphia Bible Society (volume 39, page 128), undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
      - Directions for Becoming and Continuing a Governor (according to note by James Rush, this paper was directed towards Thomas Mifflin) (volume 39, page 133), undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
      - Hints for Establishing a College at Carlisle in Cumberland County, Pennsylvania (volume 41, page 1), 1782 September 3 (Box 1, Folder 30)
      - Lang, James, John King, John Black, William Linn and Samuel Waugh regarding Hints for Establishing a College at Carlisle (volume 41, page 6), 1782 November 13 (Box 1, Folder 31)
      - Boyd, John (volume 41, page 17), 1783 February 17 (Box 1, Folder 32)
      - Reasons against founding a college at Carlisle, by Benjamin Rush (volume 41, page 30, 1783 May 20 (Box 1, Folder 33)
      - Rush, Benjamin to John Montgomery (volume 41, page 38), 1783 September 1 (Box 1, Folder 34)
      - [Rush, Benjamin] to unknown recipient (volume 41, page 95), undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
      - Rush, Benjamin to unknown recipient (volume 41, page 96), undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
      - Dickinson, John to Dr. Nesbit (copy) (volume 41, page 97), 1784 October 25 (Box 1, Folder 37)
      - Rush, Benjamin to John Montgomery (volume 41, page 107), 1785 January 15 (Box 1, Folder 38)
      - Rush, Benjamin to John Montgomery (volume 41, page 115), 1785 March 18 (Box 1, Folder 39)
      - Versailles, A. (volume 43, page 5), 1769 March 22 (Box 1, Folder 40)
      - Witherspoon, [John] regarding resignation from military (?) (volume 43, page 46), 1778 February 2 (Box 1, Folder 41)
      - Drayton, William H. and James Huntington regarding medical hospitals in Revolutionary War (volume 43, page 47), 1778 April 7 (Box 1, Folder 42)
      - Brown, W. regarding war hospitals (volume 43, page 49), 1777 December 25 (Box 1, Folder 43)
      - Morgan, John, regarding Dr. Shippen (volume 43, page 57), 1780 May 4 (Box 1, Folder 44)
      - Price, Richard (volume 43, page 61), 1780 July 22 (Box 1, Folder 45)
      - Paca, William (volume 43, page 66), undated (Box 1, Folder 46)
      - Bartlett, Josiah (volume 43, page 78), 1783 January 25 (Box 1, Folder 47)
      - Hand, Edward regarding resolution passed by Congress (volume 43, page 97), 1784 January 7 (Box 1, Folder 48)
      - Walton, G. (volume 43, page 100), 1784 June 13 (Box 1, Folder 49)
      - Bartlett, Josiah (volume 43, page 136), 1812 February 17 (Box 1, Folder 50)
      - Clymer, G. (volume 43, page 137), undated (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - C. Unbound Correspondence (arranged alphabetically), [Yi2 7402, Yi2 7403, Yi2 7404, and Yi2 7406]
      - Academia Petropolitana, 1811, 1812 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Accademia Italiano delle Scienze, Lettere, ed Arti constitution (in Italian), 1807 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Adams, John (includes 10 covers and 8 signatures), 1805-1811 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - Alexander, J., 1811 May 13 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - American Academy of Arts and Sciences regarding donation, 1800 October 6 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - American Philosophical Society regarding donation, 1806 February 7 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - Amoretti, Charles (in French), 1788 March 29 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - Arthaud, Mr. (in French), 1787, October 13 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - Barker, John, 1806 October 18 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Barnes, Thomas and Thomas Henry regarding the Literary and Philosophical Society of Manchester, 1787 January 31 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - Barrons, John regarding receipt, 1774 April 4 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - Barton, William, 1808 December 27 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - Casa Frujo, Marquis de, 1806 September (Box 2, Folder 32)
      - Chamberlaine, William regarding the Medical Society of London, 1787-1789 (Box 2, Folder 13)
      - Chew, Katherine regarding Female Association of Philadelphia for the Relief of Women and Children in Reduced Circumstances, 1808 November 17 (Box 2, Folder 14)
      - Coates, S. and W. Poyntell regarding bequeath made to Pennsylvania Hospital, 1808 February 5 (Box 2, Folder 46)
      - Collin, Nicholas regarding the Royal Academy of Sciences at Stockholm, 1793 April 10 (Box 2, Folder 15)
      - Cooper, Astley, 1811 January 10 (Box 2, Folder 16)
      - Dalcho, Federicus regarding the Societas Medica Carolinae Australis, 1795, 1805 (Box 2, Folder 72)
      - Daschkoff, Andrew, 1812 November 24 (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - Duncan, Thomas, letter regarding a hydraulic pump, 1790 August 3 (Box 3, Folder 22)
      - Elmer, Ebenezer regarding Harvean Society constitution, 1801 April 22 (Box 2, Folder 18)
      - Falconer, N and others regarding election of Rush as delegate to represent the City of Philadelphia in State Convention, 1787 November 7 (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - Fox, Edward regarding election of Rush to faculty of the University of Pennsylvania, 1792 January 23 (Box 2, Folder 20)
      - Hall, Thomas, 1806 October 12; [7402 F 40] (Box 2, Folder 21)
      - Hawes William regarding the Royal Humane Society, 1794 March-April; [7402 F 61] (Box 2, Folder 22)
      - Henderson, B., 1788 January 14 (Box 2, Folder 23)
      - Human Society of Massachusetts membership certificate, 1793 May 6 (Box 2, Folder 24)
      - Humane Society of Philadelphia membership certificate, 1805 May 10 (Box 2, Folder 25)
      - Keble John, 1787 May 3 (Box 2, Folder 26)
      - King, John, letter of condolence, 1783 August 18; [7402 f 9] (Box 2, Folder 27)
      - Kleist, Baron J. regarding award of gold medal from the King of Prussia, 1806 (Box 2, Folder 28)
      - Le Breton, Joachim (in French), 1807 March 1 (Box 2, Folder 29)
      - Linn, William, letter regarding pastoral charge in Somerset, 1784 June 21; [7402 f 11] (Box 2, Folder 30)
      - Literary and Philosophical Society of Manchester membership certificate, 1784 December 22 (Box 2, Folder 31)
      - Martin Hugh, letters regarding Dr. Bond’s cancer powder and cure of ague by venesection, 1780 January, 1781 July 1; [7402 F 7] (Box 2, Folder 34)
      - Marshall, H., incomplete letter regarding sickness, undated; [7406 F 23] (Box 2, Folder 33)
      - Massachusetts Medical Society, election as honorary member, 1787 May 20 (Box 2, Folder 35)
      - Medical Society of New Haven, presenting “their initia”, 1788 November 29 (Box 2, Folder 36)
      - Medical Society of New York regarding membership, 1808 February 25 (Box 2, Folder 37)
      - Millar, John, regarding Society of Arts, Manufactures and Commers, 1773 June 17 (Box 2, Folder 38)
      - Mitchell, S., 1812 August 4 (Box 2, Folder 39)
      - Montgomery, John, 1799 March 9 (Box 2, Folder 40)
      - More, Samuel, regarding election of Rush as Corresponding Member of the Society for the Encouragement of Art, Manufactures and Commerce, 1772 November 19 (Box 2, Folder 41)
      - Muhlenberg, Henry regarding diploma from a German academy, 1792 April 9 (Box 2, Folder 42)
      - Nekevis, William regarding Philadelphia Society for the Establishment and Support of Charity Schools, 1802 November 13 (Box 2, Folder 50)
      - Otis, H.G regarding medical condition, 1800 November 27 (Box 2, Folder 43)
      - Palloni, P. regarding Accademia Italiano delle Scienze, Lettere, ed Arti (in Italian), 1808 January 8 (Box 2, Folder 44)
      - Parker, Thomas regarding the Abolition Society, 1804 September 28 (Box 2, Folder 45)
      - Peters, Richard regarding the Agricultural Society of Philadelphia, 1807 November 2 (Box 2, Folder 47)
      - Philadelphia Dispensary subscription receipts, 1787-1794 (Box 2, Folder 48)
      - Philadelphia Medical Society, notification of his election as president of the Philadelphia Medical Society, 1794 February7 (Box 2, Folder 49)
      - Philadelphia Sunday School Society (missing), undated (Box 2, Folder 75)
      - Pintard, John Marsden, letters regarding his position as United States consul, his marriage, the Moorish Corsairs, 1784-1785 (Box 2, Folder 52)
      - Physical Society of Edinburgh, letter requesting a subscription for the purpose of procuring a royal charter, 1788 January 12 (Box 2, Folder 51)
      - Ralston, Robert regarding subscription to the African Church, 1791 November 21 (Box 2, Folder 53)
      - Randolph, Edmond, note to accompany a letter from Dr. Marcard, 1794 June 26 (Box 2, Folder 54)
      - Read, G., 1808 April 24 (Box 2, Folder 55)
      - Regia Matritensis Academia [lecture certificate], undated (Box 2, Folder 56)
      - Robertson, Walter, 1795 February 4 (Box 2, Folder 57)
      - Royal Human Society of London membership certificate, 1792 June 7 (Box 2, Folder 58)
      - Royal Jennerian Society membership certificate, 1803 May 17 (Box 2, Folder 59)
      - Rush, Benjamin to Mrs. [Bunner] regarding the death of Betsy, 1796 August 3 (Box 2, Folder 60)
      - [Rush, Benjamin] to unknown recipient regarding yellow fever, 1799 August 10 (Box 2, Folder 61)
      - Rush, Benjamin to unknown recipient regarding donation to the Female Association for the relief of indigent single women and children, 1808 November 15 (Box 2, Folder 62)
      - Rush, Benjamin to unknown recipients, 1811, 1815 (Box 2, Folder 63)
      - Rush, James, 1806 July 19 (Box 2, Folder 64)
      - Rush, James, 1809 August-September (Box 2, Folder 65)
      - Rush, James during education in Edinburgh to family, 1810 January-May (Box 2, Folder 66)
      - Rush, James during education in Edinburgh to family, 1810 June-December (Box 2, Folder 67)
      - Rush, James during education in Edinburgh to family, 1811 February-April (Box 2, Folder 68)
      - Sanford, Clark regarding the medicinal qualities of bark, 1812 January 7 (Box 2, Folder 69)
      - Smith, Samuel S., letter regarding the “metaphysical subjects of liberty and necessity” and about the course of study at Princeton University, 1796 December 5 (Box 2, Folder 70)
      - Smith, Samuel S. regarding gift to the College of New Jersey Library, 1808 September 29 (Box 2, Folder 71)
      - Spalding, Lyman regarding the New Hampshire Medical Society, 1808 May-June (Box 2, Folder 73)